Rebecca West Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Rebecca West papers
1894-1975
GEN MSS 105
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
20
(44 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence to and from West, correspondence of her husband Henry Andrews, writings of Rebecca West, writings of others, personal papers, and writings about Rebecca West.
West, Rebecca, 1892-1983
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was presented to Yale by Dame Rebecca West between 1965 and 1971.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Rebecca West Papers, approximately twenty feet in length, are composed of letters, manuscripts, and personal papers belonging to author Rebecca West and her husband Henry Andrews. The materials in the collection are dated between 1894 and 1974, with the majority dated from 1930 to 1960.
The Rebecca West Papers are divided into three series: I. Correspondence, II. Writings, and III. Personal Papers. Oversize material has been placed at the end of the collection.
Series I., Correspondence, has been separated into two subseries: Rebecca West Correspondence and Henry Andrews Correspondence. The correspondence of Rebecca West (Boxes 1-23) spans the years 1913 to 1971 and consists of letters to and from Rebecca West and numerous friends, relatives, business associates, and fans. Among the larger files of close friends are letters from Emanie Arling, S. N. Behrman, Pamela Frankau, Charlotte Haldane, Hamish Hamilton, Vyvyan Holland, Paul Hollister, Ruth Lowinsky, Anna Charles McBurney (Rebecca West's secretary), S. K. Ratcliffe, Doris Stevens, Dorothy Thompson, and Harold Nicolson. Authors represented in the collection include Arnold Bennett, Edna Ferber, Paul Gallico, Robert Graves, John Gunther, Rose Macaulay, Anäis Nin, J. B. Priestley, Vita Sackville-West, George Bernard Shaw, G. B. Stern, Virginia Woolf, and Alexander Woollcott. Files which relate to West's professional career include correspondence from A. D. Peters, the British Broadcasting Company, George T. Bye, Lawrence Langner, The New Statesman and Leader, The New Yorker, and John Van Druten.
Among the many letters that reveal West's interest in and writings on Yugoslavia are those from Anica Savic-Rebac and Stanislav Vinaver. The largest correspondence file is that of H. G. Wells, with letters dating between 1913 and 1944. Although most of these letters are brief, they are often embellished with Wells's characteristic sketches and jokes.
The Henry Andrews Correspondence (Boxes 24-27) includes letters to and from Andrews, mostly of a business nature. Many letters written in the first years after World War II document Andrews's interest in post-war Germany. Letters between Andrews and Rebecca West have been placed in the Rebecca West Correspondence, and a number of letters to Andrews from friends that relate to Rebecca West have also been placed in the appropriate files in this subseries.
Series II, Writings (Boxes 28-37), is divided into Books and Shorter Works and contains notes and manuscript drafts for a number of West's books, stories, essays, and reviews, along with printed copies of many essays and reviews of her works. Works for which there is manuscript material include Black Lamb and Grey Falcon, Endings in Earnest, The Fountain Overflows, Harriet Hume, The Meaning of Treason, The Return of the Soldier (dramatization), Saint Augustine, Strange Necessity, The Thinking Reed, and Letter to a Grandfather. Shorter Works are divided into three categories: Short Stories, Essays, and Reviews. A number of West's notebooks (including some in Books ) contain drafts of her shorter writings.
Series III, Personal Papers (Boxes 38-42), contains a variety of material belonging to Rebecca West and is arranged alphabetically by subject groups. Among these are Diaries, Financial and Business Papers, Photographs, Writings about Rebecca West, and Writings of Others. Miscellaneous items in Personal Papers have been placed at the end of the series.
Oversize contains material from the Writings and Personal Papers series.
New statesman; New Yorker (New York, N.Y.: 1925); English literature -- 20th Century; Fiction -- 20th Century; Women authors; Yugoslavia -- Description and travel; Yugoslavia -- Politics and government -- 1918-1945; Adams, Franklin P. (Franklin Pierce), 1881-1960; Bagnold, Enid; Biddle, Francis, 1886-1968; De Mille, Agnes, 1905-1993; Einstein, Lewis, 1877-1967; Gunther, John, 1901-1970; Hamilton, Hamish; Hollister, Paul M. (Paul Merrick), 1890-; Huxley, Julian, 1887-1975; Kingsmill, Hugh, 1889-1949; Lewis, Wyndham, 1882-1957; Macmillan, Harold, 1894-1986; Moore, George, 1852-1933; Nicolson, Harold, 1886-1968; Nin, Anaïs, 1903-1977; Priestley, J. B. (John Boynton), 1894-1984; Sackville-West, V. (Victoria), 1892-1962; Shaw, Bernard, 1856-1950; Spark, Muriel, 1918-2006; Stern, G. B. (Gladys Bronwyn), 1890-1973; Van Druten, John, 1901-1957; Wells, H. G. (Herbert George), 1866-1946; West, Anthony, 1914-1987; West, Rebecca, 1892-1983; Wilson, Edmund, 1895-1972; Woolf, Virginia, 1882-1941; Woollcott, Alexander, 1887-1943; A.D. Peters (Firm); Doubleday, Doran & Company; Hogarth Press; Macmillan & Co; Secker & Warburg
- Correspondence, 1914-75; Series I; 11; (27 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, is divided into Rebecca West Correspondence (boxes 1 to 21 ) and Henry Andrews Correspondence (boxes 22 to 25 ). Each contains incoming and outgoing correspondence. Correspondents with five or more letters, significant correspondents, friends of Rebecca West, and files that contain letters from Rebecca West (mainly carbons or retained copies) or letters of special interest are given separate folders, listed alphabetically. Others are placed in "Letter General" files.
  - REBECCA WEST CORRESPONDENCE
    - "A" general, 1935-57 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - A. D. Peters, 1935-56 (Box 1, Folder 2-16)
    - Adams, Franklin P., 1930 Dec 28 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Agate, James, 1933 Nov 26 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Alice Kauser and R. L. Giffen (with correspondence from Constance Collier), 1926, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Allan Wingate Limited (Anthony Gibbs), 1953-55 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - The American Scholar, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Andrews, Ernest, 1930-31 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Andrews, Henry, 1938-47 (Box 2, Folder 23-36)
    - Andrews, Henry, 1948-61 (Box 3, Folder 37-50)
    - Andrews, Henry, 1962-68, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 51-59)
    - Arling, Emanie, 1920-81, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 60-98)
    - Ashmore, Harry S., 1947 Jun 17 (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Asquith, Margot (Countess of Oxford and Asquith), 1937 Oct 22 (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - The Associated Press, Ltd., 1955 Dec 5 (Box 5, Folder 100a)
    - Association of Writers for Intellectual Liberty, 1937-38 (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - The Atlantic Monthly, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Aumonier, Stacy, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - "B" general, 1938-66, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 104-05)
    - Back, Barbara, 1952-58, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 106-07)
    - Bacon, Deborah (Box 6, Folder 108)
    - Bailey, Ed (Canada Wide Feature Service), 1948-57 (Box 6, Folder 109)
    - Baines, Cecil C., 1961-69 (Box 6, Folder 110)
    - Baker, Rowenna, 1956 Mar 23 (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - Bannenberg, Norma, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 112)
    - Barclays Bank Limited (with related correspondence), 1935-50 (Box 6, Folder 113)
    - Barker, A. L., 1966-68 (Box 6, Folder 114)
    - Barker, Ernest, 1946 May 29 (Box 6, Folder 115)
    - Barlow, Samuel, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 116)
    - Barrie, J. M. (James Matthew), 1933 Sep 15 (Box 6, Folder 117)
    - Batchelor, Denzil, 1961 Jan 31 (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - Batchelor, G., 1948 Apr 5 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - Battle, Louisa (with notation by Rebecca West), [1939] (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - Bayley, John, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 121)
    - Beaton, Cecil (and related correspondence), 1962-63 (Box 6, Folder 122)
    - Beaumanoir Hart, D., 1963 (Box 6, Folder 123)
    - Beaverbrook, William M. A., Lord, 1955, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 124)
    - Bedford, Sybille, 1967 Apr 25 (Box 6, Folder 125)
    - Beeber, Francis, 1959 Jan (Box 6, Folder 126)
    - Behrman, S. N., 1955-66 (Box 6, Folder 127)
    - Bell, Clive, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 128)
    - Benét, William Rose, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 129)
    - Benewick, R. J., 1960 (Box 6, Folder 130)
    - Bennett, Arnold, 1915-30 (Box 6, Folder 131)
    - Bennett, Dorothy (Mrs. Arnold Bennett), 1934-38, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 132)
    - Bentall, Gerald C., 1955 (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - Bentley, Nicolas (Andre Deutsch Limited), 1953-56 (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - Berenson, Bernard Berenson, Nicky, 1953-58 (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - Bergman, Ingrid (Rosellini) (with outline of film script for New Wine and related correspondence), 1952-53, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 136)
    - Berlin, Isaiah, Sir, 1953 Mar 17 (Box 6, Folder 137)
    - Bernstein, Arnold, 1957 Nov 27 (Box 6, Folder 138)
    - Bibesco, Antoine, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 139)
    - Biddle, Francis, 1946, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 140)
    - Biddle, Margaret, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 141)
    - Binder, Pearl, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 142)
    - Bircumshaw, Susan, 1962-63 (Box 6, Folder 143)
    - Birkenhead, Lord (Frederick Edwin Smith, 1st Earl of Birkenhead?), 1961 (Box 6, Folder 144)
    - Birley, Robert, 1960-61 (Box 6, Folder 145)
    - Blanche, Lesley, 1968-69 (Box 6, Folder 146)
    - Blixen, Karen, 1938 Jan 9 (Box 6, Folder 147)
    - Boardman, Frances, 1932 May 26 (Box 6, Folder 148)
    - Bodkin, Maud, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 149)
    - Bohener, Betty H., 1960 (Box 6, Folder 150)
    - Boll, Theophilus E. M., 1962 (Box 6, Folder 151)
    - Bollingen Foundation, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 151a)
    - Bonham-Carter, Victor Bonham-Carter, Mark, 1957-66 (Box 6, Folder 152)
    - Bonham-Carter, Violet, Lady, 1962, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 153)
    - Bonsal, Stephen, 1938 Sep 28 (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Booth, J. B., 1938 (Box 6, Folder 154a)
    - Borin, V. L., 1963 Aug 15 (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Borkenau, Franz (Frank), 1936, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 156)
    - Bosanquet, Theodora, 1940, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 157)
    - Bourne-Webb, Mrs., 1964 Sep 24 (Box 6, Folder 158)
    - Bower, Robert, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 159)
    - Bowra, Maurice, Sir, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 160)
    - Brackett, Charles, 1946 Jan 7 (Box 6, Folder 161)
    - Brankovitch, D. D., 1956 Feb 4 (Box 6, Folder 162)
    - Brennan, Diarmuid, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 163)
    - Brent, Romney, 1933-69 (Box 6, Folder 164)
    - Brewer, Peter, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 165)
    - Bridge, Charles, 1936-40 (Box 6, Folder 166)
    - Bridgland, Josephine, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 167)
    - British Broadcasting Company, 1951-57 (Box 6, Folder 168-71)
    - The British Council, 1939 Oct 17 (Box 6, Folder 172)
    - Brittain, Vera, 1932 Jun 6 (Box 6, Folder 173)
    - Bromfield, Louis, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 174)
    - Bronowski, J., 1962 (Box 6, Folder 175)
    - Brooke, J., 1962 (Box 6, Folder 176)
    - Brooks, Cleanth, 1963-64 (Box 6, Folder 177)
    - Brown, Fred, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 178)
    - Brown, Wenzell, 1966 Mar 14 (Box 6, Folder 179)
    - Brownell, Sonia (Pitt-Rivers), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 180)
    - Bryans, J. Lonsdale, 1968 Oct 28 (Box 6, Folder 181)
    - Bryden, Ronald, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 182)
    - Buchinger, Josefine (with related correspondence), 1935-36 (Box 7, Folder 183)
    - Buckley, William F., 1959-60 (Box 7, Folder 184)
    - Bulton, Muriel, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 185)
    - Burch, Priscilla, 1958 Feb 18 (Box 7, Folder 186)
    - Burnham, Lord, 1962 Jan 5 (Box 7, Folder 187)
    - Burt, Kendal, 1961 Oct 12 (Box 7, Folder 188)
    - Butler, Richard, 1962-68 (Box 7, Folder 189)
    - Byatt, Antonia, 1969, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 190)
    - "C" general, 1939-59 (Box 7, Folder 191)
    - Cain, James M., 1945 Dec 29 (Box 7, Folder 192)
    - Callaghan, Joseph, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 193)
    - Campbell, Ronald, 1936 Jun 8 (Box 7, Folder 194)
    - Campbell, Roy, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 195)
    - Canada Wide Feature Service, Ltd., n.d. (Box 7, Folder 196)
      Related Archival Materials note
      See also: Ed Bailey, Box 6, folder 109
    - Carswell, Catherine, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 197)
    - Cathcart, Annie R., 1956 Mar 18 (Box 7, Folder 198)
    - Central Discharged Prisoners' Aid Society, 1936 Jan 3 (Box 7, Folder 199)
    - Century Magazine, 1917 Jan 16 (Box 7, Folder 200)
    - Charles Russell and Co., 1929-50 (Box 7, Folder 201-03)
    - Cheltenham Festival ( G. A. M. Wilkinson), 1957 (Box 7, Folder 204)
    - Chen, Su-Hua Ling, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 205)
    - Chong, Claudine, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 206)
    - Clark, Kenneth, 1937 Mar 24 (Box 7, Folder 207)
    - Clemens, Cyril, 1947 Dec 25 (Box 7, Folder 208)
    - Coleridge, Georgina, Lady, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 209)
    - Cook, Eric (with letters of introduction from Paul Robeson and others), 1937 (Box 7, Folder 210)
    - Cooper, Louise Field, [1949] (Box 7, Folder 211)
    - Couch, W. T., 1943 (Box 7, Folder 212)
    - Coward, Noel, 1928-36, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 213)
    - Coward, Thomas R., 1930-56 (Box 7, Folder 214)
    - Cunard, Nancy, 1937, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 215)
    - Curran, Charles, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 216)
    - "D" general, 1930-63 (Box 7, Folder 217)
    - Dada, Roland, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 218)
    - Dafoe, Beatrice, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 219)
    - The Daily Express, 1939, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 220)
    - Daily Mail, 1939 Jan 19 (Box 7, Folder 221)
    - Danubian Club, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 222)
    - David, Gwenda, 1956 Nov 27 (Box 7, Folder 223)
    - Davies, Peter, 1932-34 (Box 7, Folder 224)
    - Day, Franklin, 1947 Jun 15 (Box 7, Folder 225)
    - Day Lewis, C. (Cecil), n.d. (Box 7, Folder 226)
    - de Chiaro, Fernando (Box 7, Folder 227)
    - Deane, Katherine Deane, Nicholas, 1961-64, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 228)
    - Deane, Martha, 1960-61 (Box 7, Folder 229)
    - Dearing, H. L., 1930 Oct 10 (Box 7, Folder 230)
    - Delafield, E. M., 1930 Nov 3 (Box 7, Folder 231)
    - De Mille, Agnes (Prude) (Box 7, Folder 232)
      See also: Box 24, folder 1096
    - Denny, Joabb, 1937 Dec 6 (Box 7, Folder 233)
    - Dent, Allan, 1960-64 (Box 7, Folder 234)
    - Denton, Hall, and Burgin, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 235)
    - Dickson, Rache Lovat, 1962-69 (Box 7, Folder 236)
    - Dinesen, Isak
      See: Karen Blixen, Box 6, folder 147
    - Dobree, Bonamy, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 237)
    - Donovan, James B., 1964 (Box 7, Folder 238)
    - Doubleday, Doran, and Company, 1934-41 (Box 7, Folder 239)
    - Douglas, Anabel, 1930 Nov 2 (Box 7, Folder 240)
    - Douglas, Norman, 1930 Dec 6 (Box 7, Folder 241)
    - Dowling, Nadia, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 242)
    - Downing, W. A., [19]38 Dec 12 (Box 7, Folder 242a)
    - Dudley, Drew, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 243)
    - Dugdale, Carol, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 244)
    - Dulles, Allan, 1964-68 (Box 7, Folder 245)
    - Dunstan, William, 1966 Sep 2 (Box 7, Folder 246)
    - Du Sautoy, Peter F., 1968 Jan 16 (Box 7, Folder 247)
    - "E" general, 1926-59 (Box 8, Folder 248)
    - Easton, Mrs., 1937-38 (Box 8, Folder 249)
    - Edalje, Maud (?), n.d. (Box 8, Folder 250)
    - Edwards, Oliver, 1956 Oct 25 (Box 8, Folder 251)
    - Eliot, Valerie (Mrs. T. S. Eliot), 1971 Jan 11 (Box 8, Folder 252)
    - Elliot, Mr., 1928 (Box 8, Folder 253)
    - Ellmann, Richard, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 254)
    - Emmet, Christopher, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 255)
      See also: Box 41, folder 1488
    - Encounter, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 256)
      See also: John Morris, Box 13, folder 588
    - English-Serbian Children's Home, 1937 Apr 20 (Box 8, Folder 257)
    - Epstein, Max, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 258)
    - Evans, Ernestine, 1936, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 259)
    - Eyre and Spottiswoode (Douglas Jerrold), 1949-50 (Box 8, Folder 260)
    - "F" general, 1932-58 (Box 8, Folder 261)
    - Faber and Faber Limited (Charles Monteith), 1955 (Box 8, Folder 262)
    - Fadiman, Clifton, 1935 Mar 7 (Box 8, Folder 263)
    - Fairfield, Isabella (Rebecca West's mother), n.d. (Box 8, Folder 264)
    - Fairfield, Letitia (Rebecca West's sister), n.d. (Box 8, Folder 265)
    - Farrer, David, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 266)
    - Farrar, John, 1926, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 267)
    - Fenby, June, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 268)
    - Ferber, Edna, 1937-56 (Box 8, Folder 269)
    - Finch-Smiles, P., 1942 (Box 8, Folder 270)
    - Fisher, H. A. L., 1939, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 271)
    - Flanner, Janet, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 272)
    - Fleming, Miss, 1960 Dec 1 (Box 8, Folder 273)
    - Fletcher, Marion, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 274)
    - Footman, David, 1941 Oct 3 (Box 8, Folder 275)
    - For Intellectual Liberty, 1938 Nov 11 (Box 8, Folder 276)
    - Forbes, Henry M., 1942 Sep 18 (Box 8, Folder 277)
    - Forbes, Rosita, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 278)
    - Ford, Anne, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 279)
    - Ford, Ford Madox
      See: Ford Madox Hueffer, Box 10, folder 405
    - Forman, Henry James, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 280)
    - Fothergill, John ( The Spreadeagle ), 1930-32 (Box 8, Folder 281)
    - [Forty-seven] 47 (John Hersey), 1947 Dec 9 (Box 8, Folder 282)
    - Frank, Helena, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 283)
    - Frank, Jerome, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 284)
    - Frankau, Pamela, 1957, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 285-86)
    - Franklin Publications, 1955, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 287)
    - Free German League of Culture, 1940 Jan 20 (Box 8, Folder 288)
    - Freemantle, Anne, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 289)
    - Freud, Sigmund, 1933 May 30 (Box 8, Folder 290)
    - Freyberg, Pankraz, 1966 Jul 11 (Box 8, Folder 291)
    - Friedberg, Judith, 1963 Jul 2 (Box 8, Folder 292)
    - Fry, Roger, 1928 (Box 8, Folder 293)
    - Fryn, W. (?), n.d. (Box 8, Folder 294)
    - "G" general, 1939-60 (Box 8, Folder 295)
    - Gaines, Bill ( The Greenville News ), 1947-49 (Box 8, Folder 296)
    - Gallico, Paul, 1948-52 (Box 8, Folder 297)
    - Gallienne, Rose Gallienne, Wilfred H., 1935-36 (Box 8, Folder 298)
    - Gardner, Mrs., [1938] (Box 8, Folder 299)
    - Garnett, David, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 300)
    - Garten, Hans, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 301)
    - Garvin, J. L., 1929 Oct 16 (Box 8, Folder 302)
    - Gavin, Catherine, 1941 Jun 9 (Box 8, Folder 303)
    - Gellis, Winifred C., 1930 Oct 26 (Box 8, Folder 304)
    - The George Square Chronicle, 1975, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 305)
    - George T. Bye and Company, 1928-47 (Box 8, Folder 306-13)
    - Gerdes, Hans, 1947 Jan 23 (Box 8, Folder 314)
    - Gerhardi, William, 1928 (Box 8, Folder 315)
    - Gibbon, Monk, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 316)
    - Gibbs, Annie, 1971 Jan 9 (Box 9, Folder 317)
    - Gilbert, E. C., 1930-33 (Box 9, Folder 318)
    - Glass, Douglas, 1932 Feb 29 (Box 9, Folder 319)
    - Godden, Rumer, 1953 Jun 11 (Box 9, Folder 320)
    - Godefroy, M., 1945 Apr 3 (Box 9, Folder 321)
    - Goldman, Emma (Solidarided International Antifacista), 1933-38 (Box 9, Folder 322)
    - Goode, W. E., 1932 Feb 23 (Box 9, Folder 323)
    - Gould, Beatrice Blackmar, 1941 Dec 1 (Box 9, Folder 324)
    - Graham, S., 1943-44 (Box 9, Folder 325)
    - Grant, Jane (Mrs. Harold Ross), 1939 Aug 13 (Box 9, Folder 326)
    - Graves, Robert, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 327)
    - Gray, Clarence Irwin, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 328)
    - Gray, Phyllis M., 1946 (Box 9, Folder 329)
    - Gray, Ruby, 1956 Mar 25 (Box 9, Folder 330)
    - Graydon, L., 1956 Mar 11 (Box 9, Folder 331)
    - Greene, Graham, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 332)
    - Gregory, Alyse, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 333)
    - Grigg, Lady, 1946 Apr 29 (Box 9, Folder 334)
    - Guinsberg, Harold
      See: The Viking Press, Box 17 folder 865
    - Gunther, John, 1940-64 (Box 9, Folder 335)
    - "H" general, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 336)
    - Hahn, Emily, 1952-54 (Box 9, Folder 337)
    - Haire, John, 1946-48 (Box 9, Folder 338)
    - Haldane, Charlotte, 1933-62 (Box 9, Folder 339)
    - Hall, John, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 340)
    - Hall, Julian, 1969 Jan 24 (Box 9, Folder 341)
    - Hambourg, Gertrude, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 342)
    - Hamilton, Hamish Hamilton, Jaimie, 1927-67 (Box 9, Folder 343)
    - Hamilton, Iain, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 344)
    - Hanford-Johnson, Pamela (Lady Snow), 1958 Mar 25 (Box 9, Folder 345)
    - Harcourt, Brace, and Company, Inc., 1954-55 (Box 9, Folder 346)
    - Hardy, Florence (Mrs. Thomas Hardy), 1922 Jul 25 (Box 9, Folder 347)
    - Harper and Brothers (Box 9, Folder 348)
    - Harrison, Gilbert A., 1963 Apr 24 (Box 9, Folder 349)
    - Harrod, Frances M. W., n.d. (Box 9, Folder 350)
    - Harrod, Roy Forbes, Sir, 1951 Feb 6 (Box 9, Folder 351)
      See also: Box 26, folder 1135
    - Hart-Davis, Rupert (with copy of letter from H. G. Wells to Hugh Walpole), 1966-70 (Box 9, Folder 352)
    - Harvard Law Review, 1953-63 (Box 9, Folder 353)
    - Haslip, Joan, 1967, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 354)
    - Hastings, Beatrice, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 355)
    - Haward, Edwin, 1936 Feb 18 (Box 9, Folder 356)
    - Hawkins, Hyman, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 357)
    - Haynes, Celia, 1969 Mar 17 (Box 9, Folder 358)
    - Hayter, Iris, Lady, 1962-70 (Box 9, Folder 359)
    - Head, Anne, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 360)
    - Heckstaff-Smith, H. W., 1929 May 31 (Box 9, Folder 361)
    - Hellmann, Ellen, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 362)
    - Hemkes, Dorothy, 1966-69 (Box 9, Folder 363)
    - Hendra, Barbara (Gervasi), 1970 (Box 9, Folder 364)
    - Henry, Richard, 1968 Jan 1 (Box 9, Folder 365)
    - Herold, J. Christopher, 1960-64 (Box 9, Folder 366)
    - Heron, Nesta M., 1960 (Box 9, Folder 367)
    - Hersch, Katherine, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 368)
    - Hersey, John, 1962 Aug 19 (Box 9, Folder 369)
    - Hewitt, John (re. Kate O'Brien), 1965 (Box 9, Folder 369a)
    - Hibbert, Eloise Talcott, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 370)
    - Hill, Carol, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 371)
    - Hiller, Wendy (Box 9, Folder 372)
    - Hilton, Susan, 1962 Sep 16 (Box 9, Folder 373)
    - Hislop, J. D., 1932 Jan 29 (Box 9, Folder 374)
    - Hodge, Merton, 1950 Jan 13 (Box 9, Folder 375)
    - Hogarth, Margaret, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 376)
    - Hogarth Press (Leonard Woolf), 1933-67 (Box 9, Folder 377)
    - Holland, Vyvyan, 1954-68 (Box 10, Folder 378)
    - Hollister, Harriet, 1962, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 379)
    - Hollister, Paul, 1947-69 (Box 10, Folder 380-87)
    - Holloway, Mark, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 388)
    - Holt, Hilda, 1961-69 (Box 10, Folder 389)
    - Holt, Norah, 1955, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 390)
    - The Home Office, 1939-40 (Box 10, Folder 391)
    - Honeyman, Catherine Honeyman, T. J., 1959-61 (Box 10, Folder 392)
    - Hope, Liza Hope, John, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 393)
    - Hopkins, Prynce, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 394)
    - Horler, Sydney, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 395)
    - Horne, Alistair, 1967 Sep 24 (Box 10, Folder 396)
    - Horrabin, Winifred, 1937-66 (Box 10, Folder 397)
    - Hoskisson, J. B., 1942 (Box 10, Folder 398)
    - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 399)
    - House, H. H., 1932 (Box 10, Folder 400)
    - Hoyt, Edwin P., 1966 (Box 10, Folder 401)
    - Huddleston, Constance, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 402)
    - Hudson, Geoffrey F., 1953-68 (Box 10, Folder 403)
    - Huebsch, Ben W., 1938-46 (Box 10, Folder 404)
      See also: Viking Press, Box 17, folder 865
    - Hueffer, Ford Maddox, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 405)
    - Huffer, Sybil, 1965, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 406)
    - Hughes, Randolf (with letters of argument about Saint Augustine ), 1933 (Box 10, Folder 407)
    - Hughes, Rupert, 1935-47 (Box 10, Folder 408)
    - Hull, R. F. A., 1945, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 409)
    - Hummel, Mary, 1960 Oct 3 (Box 10, Folder 410)
    - Humphrey, G. M., 1966 (Box 10, Folder 411)
    - Humphreys, Kathleen, 1963, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 412)
    - Hungarian Writer's Association Abroad, 1957 Oct 31 (Box 10, Folder 413)
    - Hunt, Alice, 1953-57, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 414)
    - Hunt, Violet, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 415)
    - Hurst, Fannie, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 416)
    - Hutchinson, Margaret, 1968 Nov 17 (Box 10, Folder 417)
    - Hutchinson, Ray C., 1967 (Box 10, Folder 418)
    - Hutchinson, T., 1969 (Box 10, Folder 419)
    - Hutton, Edward, 1933, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 420)